Guide To the University Of California, Santa Cruz Contemporary Classical Collection ARS.0103
Archive of Recorded Sound
University of California, Santa Cruz Contemporary Classical Collection
1928-1977
Archive of Recorded Sound
University of California, Santa Cruz
ARS.0103
11 box(es) [11 linear feet. 309 open reel tapes (11 5"; 209 7"; 89 10" reels)]
The University Of California, Santa Cruz Contemporary Classical Collection consists of live performances of classical music, mostly by twentieth century composers, on open reel tape. For the most part, recordings date from the 1960s and 70s, and include rehearsals, radio broadcasts and interviews with composers and performers.
Arrangement
Prior to accession, tapes were grouped accordingly: Series 1, 2 and 3 are all live performances. Series 1 features five-inch reels numbered 1-11. Series 2 is seven-inch reels numbered 1-118. Series 3 contains ten-inch reels numbered 1-93. Series 4 consists of items which were identified as rarer and more significant recordings. These have been assigned numbers as well, although there are many gaps. Many of these were renumbered from the previous sets. The majority of these tapes also appear to be live performances.
Access
Open for research; material must be requested at least two business days in advance of intended use. Contact the Archive for assistance.
Scope And Contents
The University Of California, Santa Cruz Contemporary Classical Collection consists of live performances of classical music on open reel tape, including rehearsals, radio broadcasts (on KPFA and KUSC) and a few interviews with composers and performers. The material dates from the late 1920s (transfers of Colin McPhee’s Bali expedition from 1928 and a 1929 Stravinsky piano roll) to the late 70s, although most are from the 1960s. While there are a few operas, the collection is heavy on instrumental music, especially organ and harpsichord music. Most significantly, the collection features many twentieth century composers, many of whom are quite obscure or under-recorded. The majority of performances are Northern Californian, but recordings are from across the United States as well as Europe. Unfortunately, little else is known of the provenance of this collection. It is unknown who made the recordings (although some are noted as copies), or what role UCSC played. The collection came to the Archive of Recorded Sound in the late 1980s. While a simple handwritten listing is available in the Archive, more detailed information is written on tape boxes and reels.
Despite the contemporary classical tag, and the fact that there is only one recording of Mozart, it would be a mistake to characterize this collection as all avant-garde (there is also only one Stockhausen performance). A variety of styles is present. Among the more well-known composers whose works are included: Andriessen, Badings, Berio, Boulez, Britten, Dallapicola, Gorecki, Harrison, Hindemith, Krenek, Matsushita, Milhaud, Nono, Penderecki, Schuller, Stravinsky, and Wagner. A few highlights: Messiaen and Cowell performing their own work, an interview with Toru Takemitsu, a documentary on Albert Schweitzer, and an Homage to Milhaud at Mills College in 1971.
Performing groups include the New York Philharmonic under Stokowski, Boulez, and Mitropoulos, the Boston Symphony Orchestra, and the Metropolitan Opera. There are recordings from festivals at Bayreuth, Tanglewood, Cabrillo, Spoleto, and Warsaw. Local performers include the San Francisco Symphony and Opera, the Oakland Symphony, the University of California Brass Ensemble, the Berkeley Piano Club, the Berkeley Free Orchestra, and the San Francisco Chamber Music Society. There are many recordings from keyboardists such as Alan Curtis, Margaret Fabrizio, Lawrence Moe, and Alice Ehlers (who is featured in an interview and lecture as well as in performance). In addition to the Balinese field recordings, there are also a few tapes of Japanese, Korean, and Indian traditional music.
University of California, Santa Cruz
- 5" reels, 11 audiotape reel(s)
  - Handel: Concerto for harpsichord and orchestra in B flat, 1949-11-29; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; 7.5 ips] (Box 1, Reel 1)
    Contents
    Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Concertos, harpsichord, orchestra. Landowska, harpsichord; New York Philharmonic, Stokowski, conductor.
    Landowska, Wanda; Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759; Stokowski, Leopold, 1882-1977; New York Philharmonic
  - Britten: A New Years Carol, I Must Be Married, Nocturne from On This Island; Festival Te Deum, undated; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 1, Reel 2)
    Britten, Benjamin, 1913-1976. Festival Te Deum. First Methodist Church of Hollywood, Wright, conductor; Brenemann, soprano.
    Britten, Benjamin, 1913-1976. Friday afternoons. Selections. Uppman, baritone; Mock, soprano; Martinez, piano.
    Wright, Norman, 1905-1982; Brenemann, Phyllis; First Methodist Church of Hollywood (Hollywood, Calif.). Choir; Martinez, Horace; Britten, Benjamin, 1913-1976; Mock, Alice; Uppman, Theodor, 1920-2005
  - Bloch: Two interludes from Macbeth, 1949-11-06; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; 7.5 ips] (Box 1, Reel 3)
    Bloch, Ernest, 1880-1959. Macbeth (Orchestral work). New York Philharmonic, Stokowski, conductor.
    Bloch, Ernest, 1880-1959; Stokowski, Leopold, 1882-1977; CBS-KNX; New York Philharmonic
  - Harris: Memories of a Child's Sunday, 1949-06-05; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; 7.5 ips] (Box 1, Reel 4)
    Harris, Roy, 1898-1979. Memories of a child's Sunday. Standard Symphony Orchestra, Barnett, conductor.
    KFI (AM); Barnett, John, 1917; Standard Symphony Orchestra; Harris, Roy, 1898-1979
  - Carpenter: Carmel concerto for orchestra, 1949-11-21; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; 7.5 ips] (Box 1, Reel 5)
    Carpenter, John Alden, 1876-1951. Carmel concerto. New York Philharmonic, Stokowski, conductor.
    New York Philharmonic; Stokowski, Leopold, 1882-1977; Carpenter, John Alden, 1876-1951
  - Kodály: String Quartet No.2, Op.10, 1949-12-04; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; 7.5 ips] (Box 1, Reel 6)
    Kodály, Zoltán, 1882-1967. Quartets, violins (2), viola, cello, no. 2, op. 10. Compinsky String Quartet. Recorded at Los Angeles County Museum.
    Compinsky String Quartet; Kodály, Zoltán, 1882-1967; Los Angeles County Museum
  - Lambert: Music for orchestra, 1949-11-06; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; 7.5 ips] (Box 1, Reel 7)
    Lambert, Constant, 1905-1951. Music, orchestra. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England), Lambert, conductor.
    KMGM; Lambert, Constant, 1905-1951; Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Lambert, Constant, 1905-1951
  - Hindemith: Die Junge Magd, Op.23, No.2, 1949-11-14; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; 7.5 ips] (Box 1, Reel 8)
    Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963. Junge Magd. Porter, contralto; Anthony, flute; Bloch, clarinet; Kundell and Daskoff, violin; Weiss, viola; Krotnick, cello. From Evenings on the Roof concert, recorded November 14, 1949. The concert was rebroadcast on KUSC, November 28, 1949.
    Anthony, Doriot; Kundell, Bernard; Bloch, Kalman; Daskoff, Kalman; KUSC (Radio station: Los Angeles, Calif.); Weiss, Abram; Porter, Caryl; Krotnick, Leonard; Trakl, Georg, 1887-1914; Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963
  - Archer and Gile: Folk songs, undated; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; 3.75 ips] (Box 1, Reel 9)
    Gile, Beverly; Archer, Frances
  - Schweitzer: Biography in Sound, 1955-12-27; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; 3.75 ips] (Box 1, Reel 10)
    Albert Schweitzer, Biography in Sound. Cousins, moderator. Ehlers and Menninger, guests. NBC program, December 27, 1955. Copied from transcription discs on November 11, 1959.
    Schweitzer, Albert, 1875-1965; Menninger, Karl, 1898-; Ehlers, Alice, 1887-1981; Cousins, Norman
  - Stravinsky: Piano sonata, 1942. Preceded by Circus Polka, 1945-06-17; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; 7.5 ips] (Box 1, Reel 11)
    Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971. Sonatas, piano (1924). Rebner, piano. San Francisco Symphony Orchestra, Kurtz, Conductor. [Note that it is assumed that this is a recording of Stravinsky's 1924 piano sonata, not his 1904 piano sonata. However, this has not been confirmed as the tape has not been auditioned].
    Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971. Circus polka. San Francisco Symphony Orchestra, Kurtz, conductor.
    Rebner, Edward; Kurtz, Efrem, 1900-1995; Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971; San Francisco Symphony Orchestra
- 7" reels, 118 audiotape reel(s)
  - Wagner: Siegfried Acts 1 and 2, 1973; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; 3.75 ips; dolby] (Box 9, Reel 1)
    Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Siegfried. 1. Aufzug. Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Siegfried. 2. Aufzug. Neidlinger, Alberich; Adam, Wanderer; Heldhof, Fafner; Cox, Siegfried; Zednick, Mime; Kamahara, Waldvogel; Höffgen, Erda; Schröder-Feinen, Brünnhilde; Stein, conductor. Recorded at the 1973 Bayreuth Festival.
    Bayreuther Festspiele; Cox, Jean; Adam, Theo; Heldhof, Heinz; Höffgen, Marga; Kamahara, Yoku; Neidlinger, Gustav, 1910-1991; Stein, Horst, 1928-2008; Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883; Zednik, Heinz; Schröder-Feinen, Ursula
  - Wagner: Siegfried Act 3, 1973; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; 3.75 ips; dolby] (Box 9, Reel 2)
    Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Siegfried. 3. Aufzug. Neidlinger, Alberich; Adam, Wanderer; Heldhof, Fafner; Cox, Siegfried; Zednick, Mime; Kamahara, Waldvogel; Höffgen, Erda; Schröder-Feinen, Brünnhilde; Stein, conductor. Recorded at the 1973 Bayreuth Festival.
    Adam, Theo; Bayreuther Festspiele; Cox, Jean; Heldhof, Heinz; Höffgen, Marga; Kamahara, Yoku; Neidlinger, Gustav, 1910-1991; Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883; Zednik, Heinz; Stein, Horst, 1928-2008; Schröder-Feinen, Ursula
  - Mozart: Cosi Fan Tutte, 1971-01-22; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 9, Reel 3)
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Così fan tutte. Includes Uppman, baritone. Recorded at the Metropolitan Opera.
    Metropolitan Opera (New York, N.Y.); Uppman, Theodor, 1920-2005; Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791
  - Jolivet; Badings; Lajtha; Blacher, circa 1948-1971; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; 3.75 ips] (Box 9, Reel 4)
    Blacher, Boris, 1903-1975. Octet, clarinet, bassoon, horn, violins, viola, cello, double bass. Members of the Munich Nonet.
    Lajtha, László, 1892-1963. Symphonies, no. 4, op. 52. Magyar Állami Hangversenyzenekar, Ferencsik, conductor. Recorded in Budapest, October 26, 1971.
    Badings, Henk, 1907-1987. Symphonies, no. 5. Nederlands Philharmonisch Orkest, Fournet, conductor. Possibly 1948.
    Jolivet, André, 1905-1974. Concertos, trumpet, instrumental ensemble. Philharmonic Orchestra of the Netherlands Broadcasting, Fournet, conductor.
    Palm and Kontarsky recital at Hertz Hall, Berkeley, CA, February 7, 1971.
    Kontarsky, Aloys; Jolivet, André, 1905-1974; Palm, Siegfried; Blacher, Boris, 1903-1975; Badings, Henk, 1907-1987; Nederlands Philharmonisch Orkest; André, Maurice; Lajtha, László, 1892-1963; Magyar Állami Hangversenyzenekar; Ferencsik, János; Fournet, Jean; Munich Nonet
  - Bloch: Suite for viola and piano; Piano quintet No.2. Harris: String quartet, circa 1958; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; 3.75 ips] (Box 9, Reel 5)
    Harris, Roy, 1898-1979. Quartets, violins (2), viola, cello.
    Bloch, Ernest, 1880-1959. Quintets, piano, strings, no. 2. Petray, piano; Names of violinists indecipherable; Rubin, viola; Kubota, cello. University of California noon broadcast, March 3, 1962.
    Bloch, Ernest, 1880-1959. Suites, viola, piano. Molnar, viola.
    Kubota, Jane; Molnar, Ferenc, 1896-1985; Bloch, Ernest, 1880-1959; Harris, Roy, 1898-1979; Rubin, Nathan, 1929-; Petray, Marjorie
  - Bach: Die Kunst der Fuge, undated; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; stereo; four track] (Box 9, Reel 6)
    Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Kunst der Fuge. Fabrizo, Wittmayer harpsichord.
    Fabrizio, Margaret; Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750
  - Distler; Henze; Powell; Villa-Lobos; Koetsier, circa 1953-1966; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 9, Reel 7)
    Villa-Lobos, Heitor. Assobio a jato. Fuller, harpsichord; Members of the New York Chamber Soloists. Hertz Hall, University of California, Berkeley. July 24, 1966.
    Powell, Mel. Miniatures, harpsichord, flute, oboe, violin, viola, cello.
    Henze, Hans Werner, 1926-2012. Absences. Erbach Chamber Music Festival. 1965.
    Distler, Hugo, 1908-1942. Concerto, harpsichord, string orchestra, op. 14. Hansen, harpsichord; Bayerischer Rundfunk. Orchester, Koetsier, conductor. 1953.
    Villa-Lobos, Heitor; New York Chamber Soloists; Koetsier, Jan, 1911-2006; Powell, Mel; Henze, Hans Werner, 1926-2012; Hansen, Elisa; Distler, Hugo, 1908-1942; Fuller, Albert; Bayerischer Rundfunk. Orchester
  - Cage; Oliveros; Ichiyanagi; Stravinsky, circa 1964-1966; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 9, Reel 8)
    Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971. Concertos, violin, orchestra, D. Abel, violin; Cabrillo Festival Orchestra, Samuel, conductor. August 1966.
    Ichiyanagi, Toshi, 1933- Music, piano, no. 4.
    Oliveros, Pauline, 1932- Duet, accordion, bandoneon.
    Cage, John. 34'46.776".
    Abel, David; Cage, John; Cabrillo Festival Orchestra; Ichiyanagi, Toshi, 1933-; Oliveros, Pauline, 1932-; Samuel, Gerhard; Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971
  - Messian: La Nativite du Seigneur; Diptyque; Livre d'rgue, undated; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; 3.75 ips] (Box 9, Reel 9)
    Messiaen, Olivier, 1908-1992. Livre d'orgue. Messiaen, organ.
    Messiaen, Olivier, 1908-1992. Diptyque. Messiaen, organ.
    Messiaen, Olivier, 1908-1992. Nativité du Seigneur. Messiaen, organ.
    Messiaen, Olivier, 1908-1992; Messiaen, Olivier, 1908-1992
  - Henry Cowell Program, undated; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; 3.75 ips] (Box 9, Reel 10)
    Cowell, Henry, 1987-1965
  - Concert by University of California Student Composers, 1964-03; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 9, Reel 11)
    Kirkman, Robert. Giggling Debutantes Decolletage. Winkler, piano; Benta, E flat clarinet.
    Nowitz, Leonard. The Repression Machine. Members of the University of Santa Barbara Symphony Orchestra; Nowitz, conductor.
    Leedy, Douglas. Quintet, 1964. Russell, clarinet; Nagata, bassoon; McSaw, trumpet; Glass, bass; Winkler, organ; Leedy, conductor.
    Thomas, John. Pieces for Joan Gallegos, for Two Pianos (1962/63). Gallegos and Thomas, pianos.
    Goodall, Blake. Eleven Songs on Japanese Haiku. Dahlgren, soprano; Imamura, piano; Doles, clarinet; Fortescue, flute.
    Chakin, David. Three Piano Pieces. Thomas, piano.
    Winkler, Peter, 1943-. Etudes for Two French Horns (1963 rev. 1964). Leedy and Green, horns.
    Brown, Earle, 1926-2002. Hodograph, no. 1. University of California Los Angeles Improvisation Ensemble.
    Bird, Joseph. Prisim, for Electronic Tape and Performers? University of California Los Angeles Improvisation Ensemble.
    Kirkman, Robert; Winkler, Judy; Goodall, Blake; Dahlgren, Carolyn; Imamura, Hiro; Doles, Nancy; Fortescue, Michael; Thomas, John; Winkler, Peter, 1943-; Green, Nelson; Chakin, David; Berta, Joseph; University of Santa Barbara Symphony Orchestra; Nowitz, Leonard; University of California Los Angeles Improvisation Ensemble; Brown, Earle, 1926-2002; Leedy, Douglas; Bird, Joseph; Russell, James; Gallegos, Joan; McSaw, Laurie; Nagata, Jeffrey; Glass, Tom
  - Venetian School Program at University of California, 1964-11-08; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 9, Reel 12)
    Monteverdi, Claudio, 1567-1643. Dixit Dominus.
    Hassler, Jacob, 1569-. Ricercar.
    Monteverdi, Claudio, 1567-1643. Salve Regina.
    Merulo, Claudio, 1533-1604. Toccata Quinto Tono
    Gabrieli, Giovanni, approximately 1554-1612. Symphoniae sacrae. In ecclesiis
    Monteverdi, Claudio, 1567-1643. Sancta Joannis.
    Gabrieli, Andrea, approximately 1533-1585. Canzoni alla francese et ricercari ariosi. Ricercar arioso, no. 1
    Gabrieli, Andrea, approximately 1533-1585. Fantasia allegra
    Gabrieli, Giovanni, approximately 1554-1612. Sacrae symphoniae. O Domine Jesu Christe
    Gabrieli, Giovanni, approximately 1554-1612. Symphoniae sacrae. Exultavit cor meum.
    Gabrieli, Giovanni, approximately 1554-1612. Toccatas, organ, C D16.
    Monteverdi, Claudio, 1567-1643. Selva morale e spirituale. Deus tuorum militum, no. 2. Christi Redemptor Omnium.
    A program broadcast live from Hertz Hall on the campus of the University of California, inaugurating the new echo organ in the hall. The University Chorus is conducted by Edward Lawton, and the organist is Lawrence Moe.
    Gabrieli, Giovanni, 1554-1612; Hassler, Jacob, 1569-; University of California, Berkeley. Chorus; Gabrieli, Andrea, 1533-1585; Moe, Lawrence, 1917-2013; Monteverdi, Claudio, 1567-1643; Lawton, Edward; Merulo, Claudio, 1533-1604
  - Fromm Concerts, Tanglewood 1964; Martinů: Harpsichord concerto, 1964-1966; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 9, Reel 13)
    Martinů, Bohuslav, 1890-1959. Concertos, harpsichord, instrumental ensemble. Salter, harpsichord; Francis Chagrin Ensemble. British Broadcasting Corporation, 1966.
    Sydeman, William, 1928-. The Lament of Elektra. Tanglewood Festival Chorus; Fromm Players; De Varon, conductor.
    Silverman, Stanley. Caruso = Chauson?, for chorus and plucked consort. First performance.
    Newell, Robert. The Trojan Women. Plassin, conductor.
    Pinkham, Daniel. Stabat Mater (1964). Riley, soprano; Tanglewood Festival Chorus; Fromm Players; Sokol, conductor. First performance.
    Tanglewood Festival Chorus; Sydeman, William, 1928-; Francis Chagrin Ensemble; Fromm Players; De Varon, Lorna Cooke; Silverman, Stanley; Sokol, Thos; Riley, Frances; Salter, Lionel; Pinkham, Daniel; Plassin, Michael; Martinů, Bohuslav, 1890-1959; Newell, Robert
  - Fromm Concerts, Tanglewood 1964, 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; 3.75 ips] (Box 9, Reel 14)
    Newell, Robert. Concerto for piano and chamber orchestra. Del Tredici, David, piano; Fromm Players, Strauss, conductor.
    Coleman, Randolph. Projection No.3. Fromm Players.
    Del Tredici, David. I hear an army. Bermonillson, soprano; Fromm Players.
    Sollberger, Harvey. Chamber variations. Fromm Players, Schuller, conductor.
    Rush, Loren, 1935-. Mandala Music. Fromm Players.
    Coleman, Randolph, 1937-. Concerto for piano and chamber orchestra. Smith, piano; Fromm Players, Mata, conductor.
    Martino, Donald, 1931-2005. Trios, piano, violin, cello. Fromm Players.
    Davidovsky, Mario, 1934- Synchronisms, no. 1. Sollberger, flute.
    Coleman, Randolph, 1937-; Bermonillson, Phyllis; Schuller, Gunther; Rush, Loren, 1935-; Newell, Robert; Mata, Eduardo; Martino, Donald, 1931-2005; Fromm Players; Del Tredici, David; Davidovsky, Mario, 1934-; Smith, Larry; Sollberger, Harvey; Strauss, Melvin
  - Cowell: Music of the World's People, undated; 1 audiotape reel(s) folders (Box 9, Reel 15)
  - Cowell: Piano Pieces, undated; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 9, Reel 16)
  - Greenwich House Music School Concert 2 of Contemporary Concert Series, 1967-1968; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; 3.75 ips] (Box 9, Reel 17)
    KPFA program celebrating the 100th anniversary of Vaughan Williams birth. Introduction by William Malloch which includes 1923 recordings of the Vaughan Williams conducting the Aeolian Symphony Orchestra. Works include: Vaughan Williams, Ralph, 1872-1958. Wasps (Suite). Overture Vaughan Williams, Ralph, 1872-1958. Old King Cole
    Martinon, Jean, 1910-1976. Vigintuor No.1. University of Chicago. Contemporary Chamber Players; Shapey, Ralph. Shapey also interviews the composer after the performance.
    Truscott, Harold. Sonatas, piano, no. 10. 1962. Ogdon, piano.
    Truscott, Harold. Sonatas, piano, no. 7. 1956.
    Salmenhaara, Erik. Symphony No.2. Finnish Radio Symphony Orchestra; Berglund, conductor.
    Novak, Ladislav. [Latin title].
    Pleskau, Raoul. Sextet.
    Powers, Maxwell. Graduations for flute and piano. Spencer, flute; Dees, piano.
    Siegmeister, Elie, 1909-1991. Sonatas, piano, no. 2. Mandell, piano.
    Berg, Alban, 1885-1935. Lieder. Daugherty, vocalist; Chamberlain, piano.
    Carlins, William. Music for oboe, bass clarinet, and piano.
    Rovics, Howard. Cybernetic study for flute and piano. Pagano, flute; Rovics, piano
    Rovics, Howard. Cybernetic study for flute and piano. Pagano, flute; Rovics, piano.
    Spencer, Patricia, 1943; Powers, Maxwell; Pleskau, Raoul; Dess, German; Chamberlain, Ann; Radion sinfoniaorkesteri; Mandell, Alan; Siegmeister, Elie, 1909-1991; Daugherty, Lee; University of Chicago. Contemporary Chamber Players; Salmenhaara, Erik; Novák, Ladislav, 1872; Vaughan-Williams, Ralph; Malloch, William F.; Carlins, William; Martinon, Jean, 1910-1976; Ogdon, John, 1937-1989; Truscott, Harold; Berglund, Paavo, 1929-2012; Rovics, Howard; Berg, Alban, 1885-1935; Pagano, Anthony; Shapey, Ralph, 1921-2002
  - U.C Student Composers, circa 1946-1962; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch] (Box 9, Reel 18)
    Krenek, Ernst, 1900-1991. Symphonic elegy. 1946. CBC Orchestra.
    Roldán, Amadeo, 1900-1939. Rítmica, no. 1. Aptos Wind Players. Spring 1962.
    Kauder, Hugo, 1888-1972. Wind Quartet. Aptos Wind Players. Spring 1962.
    Szabelski, Bolesław, 1896-1979. Preludes for chamber orchestra.
    Krenz, Jan, 1926. Music for solo clarinet.
    Chaitkin, David, 1938-2011. Three piano pieces. Tartak, piano.
    Epstein, Paul, 1938. Two Autumn songs: Elegy and Cradle Song. Swall, voice; ensemble; Epstein, conductor.
    Arnett, John E. Two movements for piano. Isidor, piano.
    Konaus, Monroe. Two motets. University of California Chorus.
    Williams, Howard. Piece for piano. Tartak, piano.
    University of California, Berkeley. Chorus; Swall, Corinne; CBC Symphony Orchestra; Isidor, Michael; Arnett, John; Konaus, Monroe; Szabelski, Bolesław, 1896-1979; Krenz, Jan, 1926-; Roldán, Amadeo, 1900-1939; Kauder, Hugo, 1888-1972; Williams, Howard; Krenek, Ernst, 1900-1991; Chaitkin, David, 1938-2011; Epstein, Paul, 1938; Tartak, Marvin; Aptos Wind Players
  - Anglebert; Austin; Behrman; Budd; Bull; Canay; Couperin; Gnazzo; Le Clerc; Michaux, circa 1967-1968; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; 3.75 ips; four track] (Box 9, Reel 19)
    Budd, Alexander. Seven. Austin, performer.
    First Festival of Live Electronic Music. Mills College and University of California, Davis. Austin, Larry. Accidents. Austin and Tudor, performers. Gnazzo, Anthony, 1936-. Long Distances. Tudor and students from Mills College, performers. Featuring works by Larry Austin, and Anthony Gnazzo, then Director of Mills College Tape Center. Performers include Larry Austin and David Tudor.
    Canay, Marcel? Sonata for two violins and piano.
    Michaux, Paul Baudoca, 1930-. Synonance, or Assonance?
    Le Clerc, Michael, 1914-. Cantebise, suite for cello and harpsichord. Antoine, harpsichord; de Ser, cello. December 1, 1967. Movements: The Forbidden Fruit; Dolce far minute-valse?; Arithmetic.
    Couperin, François, 1668-1733. Pièces de clavecin, 4e livre. No 24.
    Bull, John, -1628. Walsingham.
    Anglebert, J. Henry d' (Jean Henry), 1629-1691. Selections. May 31, 1968.
    First Festival of Live Electronic Music. Mills College and University of California, Davis. Austin, Larry. Accidents. Austin and Tudor, performers. Gnazzo, Anthony, 1936-. Long Distances. Tudor and students from Mills College, performers.
    Featuring works by Larry Austin, and Anthony Gnazzo, then Director of Mills College Tape Center. Performers include Larry Austin and David Tudor.
    Behrman, David. Run-through.
    Le Clerc, Michael, 1914-; Couperin, François, 1668-1733; Bull, John, -1628; Anglebert, J. Henry d' (Jean Henry), 1629-1691; Austin, Larry; Budd, Alexander; Behrman, David; Michaux, Paul Baudoca, 1930-; Antoine, Lucienne; Tudor, David, 1926-1996; Canay, Marcel; de Ser, Roger; Gnazzo, Anthony, 1936-
  - Offenbach: La Perichole. Mozart: Don Giovani, 1971; 1 audiotape reel(s) [1/4 inch; 3.75 ips; mono; four track] (Box 9, Reel 20)